Vincent Varghese

Covington, WA 98042

Phone: 516 384 4461 | Email: <u>VinAVarghese@gmail.com</u> LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vincent-varghese

Portfolio: https://vav-portfolio.herokuapp.com/ | GitHub: https://github.com/VinAVarghese

Summary

A Full Stack Developer leveraging over five years of management experience to produce meaningful outputs while cultivating healthy team dynamics. Fluent in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and the full MERN stack with a full-stack development certificate from the University of Washington. Known among peers for strengthening teams and producing successful deliverables.

Skills

Public Speaking/Communication	JavaScript
Project & Team Management	React.js
Partner & Client Relations	Node.js
Social Media Management	MongoDB
iWork & Microsoft Office Suites	mySQL
Photoshop	Git

Projects

MixMe

GitHub https://tinyurl.com/yx9tevn6

| Link https://tinyurl.com/y598ysr2

- MixMe is a web application that searches drink recipes by ingredients.
- Led front-end development on this project, creating responsive layouts and designing the UX/UI. Also developed creative assets
- Tools: Foundation, CSSShake, CSS, JSON & AJAX

PLANIT

| GitHub https://tinyurl.com/yyr4x2jr

Link https://tinyurl.com/yxfjql36

- PLANIT is a collaborative, group trip planner
- Led front-end development. Developed creative assets and directed UX/UI
- Tools: Ant Design, React.js, React-animateon-scroll, React-scroll, MongoDB

Spontaneously Now

| GitHub https://tinyurl.com/yy2rqxny

Link https://tinyurl.com/y22c6alr

- Spontaneously Now is a web application that suggests spontaneous activities and doubles as a journal.
- Led back-end development, integrating 4 3rd-party APIs with DB. Developed creative assets & directed UX/UI
- Tools: Foundation, CSSAnimate, Sequelize, Express, Moment, Handlebars, AXIOS, & AJAX

Experience

Consultant 2020 – 2020

The Church Co Remote

- Word Press data entry, management and content design
- Successfully maintaining customer satisfaction with prompt and excellent work

Acting District Manager

2019 – 2019

CityMD

Seattle, WA

- Responsible for day to day clinic operations for 8 urgent care clinics across the greater Seattle area during a company transition
- Oversaw manager schedules and clinic staffing
- Conducted all-staff meetings and one-on-one performance reviews/counseling

Site Manager 2018 – 2019

CityMD Seattle, WA

- Oversaw all day to day clinic operations and managed clinic flow
- Was directly responsible for clinic's customer service experience and produced the top Press
 Ganey scores in the region for customer satisfaction
- Conducted interviews, performance reviews, and staff counseling

Assistant Site Manager

2017 - 2018

CityMD

Seattle, WA

- Assisted the Site Manager in all their day to day duties
- Led the frontline staff, ensuring excellent customer service in every interaction
- Entrusted to solely preform Site Manager duties for six months to help Senior/District
 Management during a transitional period

Information & Public Awareness Manager

2014 - 2016

Vision Rescue

Mumbai, MH, India

- Increased social media engagement from no online activity to a global presence across various platforms
- Created and oversaw a reporting system to relay on-field impact data to partners
- Recruited and liaised local and international partnerships, effectively presenting to corporate boards and larger groups

Education

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Washington, Seattle, WA

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelors Degree: Alphacrucis College, Sydney, NSW, Australia

A Bachelors in Contemporary Ministry, focusing on leadership. Upon graduating, received the "Outstanding Graduate Award: Exemplary Achievement & Leadership"